melmagazine.com 2018-11-04

# Privacy - MEL Magazine

Last updated: 9/9/18

This Privacy Policy applies to information collected by MEL Industries (“MEL,” “we,” “our” or “us”) when you visit our website, [www.melmagazine.com](https://melmagazine.com/), connect with us through branded pages on third party platforms ( _i.e_ , social networking services), or through other online communications (collectively, the “Services”). 

This Privacy Policy explains what information may be collected from or about you through the Services, how such information may be used and/or shared with others, how we safeguard it and how you may access and control certain uses. By using the Services, you agree to the collection, use, and disclosure of your information as described in this Privacy Policy.  If you do not, please do not use the Services.

This Privacy Policy is hereby incorporated into and forms part of our **Terms of Use**.

Please note that the Services are operated in and targeted to consumers in the United States.  The Services are not intended for residents of the European Union or Canada or any other country outside the United States.  If you are located in the European Union, Canada or elsewhere outside of the United States, please be aware that any information you provide to us will be transferred to the United States and may be stored on servers in the United States.

**QUICK GUIDE TO CONTENTS  **

  1. INFORMATION COLLECTION
  2. HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION COLLECTED 
  3. SHARING OF INFORMATION 
  4. YOUR CHOICES AND OPT-OUT
  5. CHILDREN’S PRIVACY 
  6. SECURITY OF YOUR INFORMATION 
  7. OTHER SITES 
  8. DATA STORAGE 
  9. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY 
  10. CONTACT US 

***

  1. **INFORMATION COLLECTION  **
  2. **Information You Provide To Us**

MEL collects information from you when you choose to share it with us.  This includes when you use the Services, sign up for newsletters or our email list, use certain features on the Services, access, upload or download content, request customer support, or otherwise contact or communicate with us.  The information we collect may include your name and e-mail address.  

You may also be given the option to link to your Facebook, Twitter or other social media account on the Services. When you do, we may automatically receive certain information from you based upon your privacy settings on those sites. This may include, but may not be limited to, name, user name, demographic information, updated address or contact information, location, interests, and publicly-observed data, such as from social media and online activity. 

  1. **Information Collected Automatically**

Whenever you visit or interact with the Services, MEL, or its service providers, may use a variety of technologies, such as cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, log files, or other technologies that automatically or passively collect information about your online activity. 

Please note that we may automatically collect the following information about you: 

**_Usage Information_** **:**  We may collect information about your use of the Services, including the date and time you visit the Services, the areas or pages of the Services that you visit, the amount of time you spend viewing or using the Services, the number of times you return to the Services, other click-stream or site usage data, emails that you open, forward or click-through to our Services, and other sites that you may visit. 

**_Device Information_**. We may automatically collect your IP address or other unique identifier or information from the computer, mobile device, tablet or other device you use to access the Services, including but not limited to your browser type, device type, operating system, software version, phone model, phone operating system, and the domain name from which you accessed the Services.

**_Third Party Service Providers_**. We may use third party service providers to support the Services.  Some of these service providers may use technology such as cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, log files, or other technologies to receive, collect, and store information on our behalf. 

  1. **Information Received from Other Third Parties**

We may obtain information about you from other trusted third party sources to update or supplement the information that you provide or that we collect automatically. We may also receive information about you from our partners and service providers, (including, for example, business partners, analytics vendors, advertising networks and search information providers).  

We may use this information to help us maintain the accuracy of the information we collect, and for internal business analysis or other business purposes. 

  1. **Combination of Information**

We may combine the information we receive from you and about you, including information you provide to us and information we automatically collect through the Services, and from third party sources.  This combined information may be used in any manner detailed in this Privacy Policy.

  2. **HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION COLLECTED**

We may use the information about you for a variety of business purposes, including, for example, to: 

  * respond to your questions or requests, and communicate with you when necessary; 
  * review the usage and operations of our Services, develop new products or services and to enhance or improve our content, products, and services;
  * provide you with content, advertisements, offers and promotions offered by MEL or on behalf of our partners and affiliates on the Services, or to provide your with news and other information we think will be of interest to you on the Services or via email;
  * protect the security or integrity of the Services and our business, such as by protecting against and preventing fraud, claims and other liabilities, and managing risk exposure, including by identifying potential hackers and other unauthorized users; 
  * use your data in an aggregated non-specific format for analytical or other business purposes; and
  * use your information for other purposes as disclosed at the time you provide your personal information or otherwise with your consent.

  3. **SHARING OF INFORMATION  **

The information collected or generated through your use of the Services may be shared by you or by us as described below.  

  1. **Sharing of Information by You**

The Services offer many ways to find, enjoy, and share content. Your activity in connection with the Services may include filling out surveys, participation in online communities, “liking” or “sharing” MEL content to your social media accounts or pages or otherwise interacting with the Services.  Any information you may disclose on the Services, in blogs, on message boards, or on other public areas on the Services or other third-party websites, applications, or services that the Services may link to, becomes public information. Please exercise caution when disclosing personal information in these public areas.

  1. **Sharing of Information by Us**

We may share the information collected from or about you in the following limited ways:

**_Third Party Service Providers_** **.**  We may share your information with third party service providers that provide business, professional or technical support functions on our behalf. This includes, but may not be limited to, service providers that host or operate the Services; payment processors; analyze data; provide customer service; postal or delivery services, and sponsors or other third parties that participate in or administer any promotions. 

**_Business Transfers_** **.**  In the event that another entity acquires us or all or substantially all of our assets, or assets related to the Services, your information may be disclosed to such entity as part of the due diligence process and will be transferred to such entity as one of the transferred assets. Also, if any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding is brought by or against us, all such information may be considered an asset of ours and as such may be sold or transferred to third parties. Finally, information described in this paragraph may also be disclosed for due diligence purposes in connection with any proposed transaction of the sorts described in this paragraph.

**_Legal Disclosures; Safety_** **.** ** _  _**We may transfer and disclose your information to third parties to comply with a legal obligation; when we believe in good faith that the law requires it; at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation; to verify or enforce our **Terms of Use**  or other applicable policies; to detect and protect against fraud, or any technical or security vulnerabilities; to respond to an emergency; or otherwise to protect the rights, property, safety, or security of third parties, users of the Services, MEL, or the public. 

**_Aggregate or Anonymous Non-Personal Information_**. We may share aggregate or anonymous non-personal information with third parties for their business use.

  4. **YOUR CHOICES AND OPT-OUT**
  5. **Cookies, Tracking Options and California Do Not Track Disclosures**

Certain parts of the Services require cookies. You are free to set your browser or operating system settings to limit certain tracking or to decline cookies, but by doing so, you may not be able to use certain features of the Services or take full advantage of all of our offerings. Please refer to your device’s settings or your Internet browser’s “Help” section for more information on how to delete and/or disable your device or browser from receiving cookies or controlling your tracking preferences. 

Our system may not respond to Do Not Track requests or headers from some or all browsers.  

  1. **Access and Updates to Your Information**

If you wish to verify, correct, or update any of your personal information, you can contact us at the e-mail in the “Contact Us” section below. 

  1. **Unsubscribing from our Marketing Communications**

You can unsubscribe from our marketing email communications at any time by (1) unsubscribing or following the instructions contained within the email, or (2) contacting us at the e-mail provided in the “Contact Us” section below. 

  1. **Your California Privacy Rights**

MEL does not disclose personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes.  

Nonetheless, California law permits residents of California to request certain details about how their personal information is shared with third parties or affiliated companies for direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please contact us at: [Legal@melindustries.com](mailto:Legal@melindustries.com). You must put the statement “Your California Privacy Rights” in the subject field. We are not responsible for notices that are not properly labeled or sent, or do not have complete information.

  5. **CHILDREN’S PRIVACY**

Protecting children’s privacy is important to us. We do not direct the Services to, nor do we knowingly collect any personal information from, children under the age of thirteen.  If MEL learns that a child under the age of thirteen has provided personally identifiable information through the Services, we will use reasonable efforts to remove such information from our files.

  6. **SECURITY OF YOUR INFORMATION  **

We use certain reasonable security measures to help protect your personal information. However, no electronic data transmission or storage of information can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  Please note that we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. You use the Services and provide us with your information at your own risk.  If we share information with a third party, as detailed in this privacy policy, we shall use all reasonable efforts to ensure that they keep the information secure and only use the information consistent with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

  7. **OTHER SITES  **

The Services may contain links to third-party websites, which may have privacy policies that differ from our own.  We are not responsible for the practices of such sites. 

The Services may also offer you the ability to interact with social plugins from social media sites, which may allow us and/or the social media site to receive data from or about you. In some cases, we may know that you clicked on a social plugin, such as a Twitter Follow button, or receive other information from the social media sites. Similarly, if you have previously provided personal information to a third-party operating a plug-in on the Services, then such third-party may recognize you on the Service. Your use of social network plugins is subject to each social media site’s privacy policy, which may be different from ours, so please read these policies carefully to understand their policies and your options. As with linked sites, we have no control over the information that is collected, stored, or used by social network plugins, and are not responsible for the practices of such sites. 

  8. **DATA STORAGE**

Your personal information may be stored on servers in the United States and is subject to the laws of the United States, where the data protection and other laws may differ from those of your country of residence. Your personal information may be disclosed in response to inquiries or requests from government authorities or to respond to judicial process in the countries in which we operate. 

  9. **CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY  **

Any changes we may make to our Privacy Policy will be posted on this page. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree or consent to these updates or changes, do not continue to use the Services. If we make a material change to this Privacy Policy, we will provide appropriate notice to you.

  10. **CONTACT US  **

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at: 

Attn: MEL Industries Privacy Officer  
Address: 13335 Maxella Ave., Marina del Rey, CA 90292  
RE: MEL INDUSTRIES PRIVACY POLICY

E-Mail: [Legal@melindustries.com](mailto:Legal@melindustries.com)

Alternatively, please go to melmagazine.com and click on the Contact Us link.
